<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Fully Modulated</title>
        <description>Fully Modulated is a podcast and blog that covers radio, broadcasting technology, industry news, and audio engineering topics.</description>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
        <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 00:46:40 -0600</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 00:46:40 -0600</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>Jekyll v4.4.1</generator>
        
            <item>
                <title>Turkey, Transmitters, And Thanks</title>
                <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-foundation-of-broadcast-resilience&quot;&gt;My Foundation of Broadcast Resilience&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gratitude is more than a seasonal sentiment in broadcasting for me; it’s the quiet force that keeps my signals steady when budgets thin, formats flip, and the clock creeps past 2 a.m.&lt;/strong&gt; This reflection traces my journey from early curiosity to a full-fledged career in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Broadcast_engineering&quot;&gt;radio engineering&lt;/a&gt;, shaped by mentors who answered my repeat questions with patience and colleagues who stayed on the line until my silence turned back into sound. The thread running through each stage has always been simple: people make the difference. That truth sits at the heart of radio’s resilience, where creativity meets constraint and connection beats complexity. On a holiday built around thanks, it feels right for me to slow the pace and call that out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;early-beginnings-my-pull-toward-live-audio&quot;&gt;Early Beginnings: My Pull Toward Live Audio&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My origin story begins with a pull toward &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Live_sound_mixing&quot;&gt;live audio&lt;/a&gt; long before my first official job. There’s an electricity I still feel in turning a fader, hearing the return in real time, watching meters move because a choice I made allowed them to move. In 2014, the first door opened for me, and the day-to-day introduced more than knobs and schedules; it revealed a system, a culture, and a craft. I learned that every show relies on a hundred small dependencies, and that my confidence grows not from flawless days, but from the recoveries. That early immersion planted both humility and hunger in me—the humility to ask for help and the hunger to understand why a fix works so I can make it work again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;broadcast-engineering-where-physics-meets-logistics&quot;&gt;Broadcast Engineering: Where Physics Meets Logistics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By 2018, my path turned to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Broadcast_engineering&quot;&gt;broadcast engineering&lt;/a&gt;, where my work became equal parts physics, logistics, and calm under stress. &lt;strong&gt;Transmitters&lt;/strong&gt; stopped being black boxes and started being stories: line voltage, thermal loads, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Studio/transmitter_link&quot;&gt;STL links&lt;/a&gt;, antennas that don’t care about my calendar, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Radio_propagation&quot;&gt;propagation&lt;/a&gt; that laughs at my plans. I discovered the art of the 2 a.m. save, the triage between what must be done now and what can wait, and the discipline to document so the next person is faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;network-engineering-at-scale&quot;&gt;Network Engineering at Scale&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then scale arrived. In 2025, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_engineering&quot;&gt;network engineering&lt;/a&gt; added &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IP_routing&quot;&gt;IP routing&lt;/a&gt;, redundancy models, remote contribution, and clocking that keeps entire clusters in sync. My mission expanded from a local carrier to a backbone built on timing, monitoring, and trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-human-web-community-and-mentorship&quot;&gt;The Human Web: Community and Mentorship&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet the tech has never been the whole story for me. The industry’s human web—on-air hosts, producers, directors, sellers, engineers, managers—creates a loop of energy that sustains my work. Budget cuts and staff changes may hit morale, but shared purpose refuels it. Conferences and shop visits have become my classrooms; hallway chats transmit knowledge much faster than memos. &lt;strong&gt;Mentors&lt;/strong&gt; have anchored my career by turning confusion into clarity one small step at a time. Colleagues have become friends because nothing bonds like solving a dead-air mystery minutes before drive time. The value of that community is hard for me to quantify and easy to feel; it shows up in quick texts, spare parts loaned, and the laughter that follows the fix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;listeners-complete-the-circuit&quot;&gt;Listeners Complete the Circuit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Listeners complete the circuit&lt;/strong&gt; for me. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Podcast&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt; that explores codecs, transmitter sites, and radio lore might seem niche at launch, but curiosity is more common than I once imagined. Feedback loops from my audience sharpen episodes, correct my misses, and surface new angles. When people share their own station stories or ask me about a signal path, they become co-authors of the archive. That engagement keeps my work fresh and pushes each deep dive to be clearer and truer. Thanks is due to everyone who cares enough to listen, to challenge, and to celebrate the craft that carries voices farther than any single room could.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-statement-of-purpose&quot;&gt;A Statement of Purpose&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, this Thanksgiving note becomes my statement of purpose. I will keep building systems that are sturdy and simple to maintain. I will keep teaching the next engineer not only what to do, but why. I will keep honoring the hosts and producers who make the air worth carrying. I will keep showing up when the clock says otherwise. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Radio_broadcasting&quot;&gt;Radio&lt;/a&gt; is an old medium that stays young because people like us keep renewing it with skill and heart. &lt;strong&gt;Gratitude is how I remember that—and how I find the strength to do it again tomorrow.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 07:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/turkey-transmitters-and-thanks</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/turkey-transmitters-and-thanks</guid>
                
                <category>Episodes</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Tyler Woodward Project: A Fresh Name For The Same Curious Tech Brain</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;After the New Year, I am retiring the Fully Modulated name and bringing everything under a new banner: The Tyler Woodward Project. This is not a new show or a reset, it is simply a better reflection of what I actually do and what I want to talk about going forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I launched Fully Modulated, I wanted a space to talk about broadcasting. I have spent my career in and around transmitters, studios, RF chains, STL links, and all of the weird glue that keeps radio and TV stations on the air. That focus helped me get started and it attracted some great listeners who care about the same things. Over the last year, though, I have realized that tying everything to “broadcasting” in the title makes it feel like I am not allowed to wander outside the transmitter building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In reality, my day job and my interests cover a much wider slice of technology. I spend just as much time on networking, security, automation, data privacy, and the broader tech stack that supports media as I do on traditional RF. I also live in Linux terminals, self-hosted services, and open source tools, and I care a lot about the communities and philosophies behind them. I enjoy talking about routing, firewalls, protocols, logging, privacy tooling, and the open source projects that make all of that possible for both hobbyists and professionals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tyler Woodward Project gives me room to bring all of that into the same feed without feeling like I am breaking my own premise. It is me, it is who I am, and it reflects the way my brain actually jumps between topics in the real world. I might talk about firewalls one week, social media issues the next, and then dive into audio over IP, streaming chains, or some strange bug I chased down at a transmitter site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is what is actually changing. The name will change from Fully Modulated to The Tyler Woodward Project. The logo and visual branding will get a refresh to match that new identity. The website and social accounts will be updated to point to the new name. New episodes will not be limited to broadcast engineering, they will also dive into general tech, networking, cybersecurity, Linux, open source, and whatever else I am building, fixing, or breaking in a given week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is what is not changing. I am still the host. The format, tone, and style are staying the same. I still want this to feel like sitting down with a fellow engineer who explains things clearly and is not afraid to nerd out over details or show config snippets and shell commands. If you subscribe to the show now, you do not have to touch anything. The feed is the same, the archive stays online, and your app will simply start showing the new name and artwork once the switch happens. Your podcast follows stay exactly the same and most of the social media accounts you already know will stay the same too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to follow along elsewhere, you can find me on Threads, Instagram, and Bluesky as @tylerwoodward.me. Apple Podcasts, Spotify, and YouTube will all convert over to the new name when the time comes, so you can keep listening wherever you already are without changing a thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have spent almost a year working on Fully Modulated as a brand. It has been fun to design, build the site, and see those first downloads and messages roll in. At the same time, I can feel the limits of the original framing every time I sit down to plan content. The Tyler Woodward Project is my way of fixing that. It lets me keep everything that works while opening the door to broader tech and open source conversations I have wanted to have all along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you have enjoyed Fully Modulated, thank you. You are coming with me. Same host, same brain, same curiosity, just with a name that feels a little more honest about what this thing actually is and where it is going.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 23:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/the-tylerwoodward-project</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-tylerwoodward-project</guid>
                
                <category>Blog</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>How FCC Spectrum Auctions Push Broadcasters Toward Internet-First Delivery</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;changes-facing-broadcasters&quot;&gt;Changes Facing Broadcasters&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Broadcasters in radio and television face another wave of transformation as the FCC prepares to auction additional C-band spectrum. For decades, the 3.7 to 4.2 GHz slice of C-band has provided dependable coast-to-coast feeds for news, sports, and network programming. This spectrum resists rain fade and long distances, reliably serving thousands of stations. However, rising spectrum demand and tighter deadlines mean the challenge is not nostalgia but preserving reliability as the band shrinks. Success depends on strategy, redundancy, and creatively mixing legacy and modern tools to build resilience suited to future auctions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;signal-path-evolution&quot;&gt;Signal Path Evolution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Broadcast signal paths have always evolved. Initially, networks relied on leased analog lines, which brought their own hum and crosstalk. When those links failed, tapes were physically mailed for syndication. Microwave relays improved reliability; then, satellites made live national feeds accessible and affordable. Installing a dish used to be the answer for distribution. Over time, IP-based solutions grew in importance, including ISDN, digital connections, new codecs, and real-time transport over the internet. While early skepticism focused on last mile reliability issues and jitter, technologies like bonded links, smarter routing, path diversity, and cloud distribution matured and changed the cost and reliability calculations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;engineering-for-failure&quot;&gt;Engineering for Failure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every system in broadcast engineering eventually fails. Phone lines cut out, dishes suffer damage, fiber is at risk from construction, and wireless links are affected by storms. Failover is essential. Modern resilience involves redundancy across multiple networks: a primary fiber link paired with Starlink and a 5G router, or a satellite feed backed by dual ISPs. The important factor is system response during failure. Solutions require automated switchover, active monitoring, and frequent off-hours testing. Disrupting the main feed should trigger a prompt, observable recovery process. If you discover a faulty backup only when it is needed, your diagram was misleading, and you had no real redundancy in practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hybrid-and-redundant-solutions&quot;&gt;Hybrid and Redundant Solutions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C-band continues to excel in weather resilience, but spectrum reduction creates new pressures. Ku-band can provide occasional support, but it is prone to rain outages for critical feeds. Fiber offers low latency and high-speed data delivery, but many rural stations do not have diverse and independent access routes. True resilience is achieved through hybrid systems. Bonding and aggregating connections across fiber, cellular, and LEO satellite networks deliver robustness against single-point failures. Techniques such as forward error correction, congestion-aware protocols, secure transport standards (like SRT or RIST), and cloud delivery with multi-region failover can match or outperform legacy satellite reliability when thoughtfully arranged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;culture-and-mindset-shifts&quot;&gt;Culture and Mindset Shifts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This transformation is cultural as much as technical. Engineers accustomed to satellite must start viewing IP delivery as one essential layer. Risk should be distributed, never placed on a single technology. Use diverse ISPs, separate physical paths, independent power sources, and varied last-mile technologies. Comprehensive monitoring is necessary. Track packet loss, latency, and failover events; record switchover times; and practice disaster recovery. Runbooks should clarify escalation steps and responsibilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe height=&quot;175&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; title=&quot;Media player&quot; src=&quot;https://embed.podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/how-fcc-spectrum-auctions-push-broadcasters-toward/id1803865840?i=1000738104440&amp;amp;itscg=30200&amp;amp;itsct=podcast_box_player&amp;amp;ls=1&amp;amp;mttnsubad=1000738104440&amp;amp;theme=auto&quot; id=&quot;embedPlayer&quot; style=&quot;border: 0px; border-radius: 12px; width: 100%; height: 175px; max-width: 660px;&quot; sandbox=&quot;allow-forms allow-popups allow-same-origin allow-scripts allow-top-navigation-by-user-activation&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay *; encrypted-media *; clipboard-write&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 08:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/how-fcc-spectrum-auctions-push-broadcasters-toward-internet-first-delivery</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-fcc-spectrum-auctions-push-broadcasters-toward-internet-first-delivery</guid>
                
                <category>Episodes</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>AM Stereo’s Lost Legacy! Could C-QUAM and the Harris AMS-G1 Have Saved Music on AM?</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Most people hear &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/AM_broadcasting&quot;&gt;AM radio&lt;/a&gt; and think of a thin voice cutting through static, not music that lands with weight and space. That assumption is learned, not inevitable. A late-night dive into YouTube clips of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/AM_stereo&quot;&gt;AM stereo&lt;/a&gt;—especially stations using &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/C-QUAM&quot;&gt;Motorola’s C-QUAM system&lt;/a&gt;—can reset your ears in seconds. The sound is wide and punchy, and on a good signal it feels close to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/FM_broadcasting&quot;&gt;FM&lt;/a&gt;. That shock opens a bigger question: if AM could carry stereo well, why didn’t it become the default? The answer sits at the intersection of engineering elegance, regulatory missteps, market timing, and the slow inertia of consumer gear, all of which turned a promising idea into a footnote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-am-and-fm-differ&quot;&gt;How AM and FM Differ&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start with the basics. AM and FM are different ways to move audio: &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amplitude_modulation&quot;&gt;AM varies amplitude&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frequency_modulation&quot;&gt;FM shifts frequency&lt;/a&gt;. For decades, AM stayed locked to mono while FM claimed stereo and, with it, music. By the 1970s, listeners wanted albums and mixtapes that panned guitars and synths across the dash. AM still carried hits, but its image lagged. Multiple firms built competing AM stereo systems—Motorola, Magnavox, Harris, and Kahn—proving the concept worked. C-QUAM stood out because it folded left and right into a form that old mono sets could still decode, while new receivers unlocked the stereo layer. Think of it as a hidden channel riding shotgun with the legacy signal, backward compatible without gutting infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-fccs-fatal-hesitation&quot;&gt;The FCC’s Fatal Hesitation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then came the deciding moment that never quite decided anything. After long tests, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fcc.gov/&quot;&gt;FCC&lt;/a&gt; first blessed Magnavox, then reversed course and let the market fight it out. The result was confusion. Some broadcasters chose one system, others picked another, and car makers shipped radios that spoke only certain dialects. Shoppers heard mono or mismatched stereo depending on the city and the dashboard. Retailers scaled back inventory. By the time C-QUAM became the U.S. standard in 1993, AM music formats had already fled to FM, leaving talk, news, and sports to fill the band. The technology arrived ready; the audience had moved on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;practical-hardware-implementation&quot;&gt;Practical Hardware Implementation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the hood, the hardware was refreshingly practical. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.broadcast.harris.com/&quot;&gt;Harris AMS-G1 exciter&lt;/a&gt; could slot into an existing chain, transform the feed into C-QUAM stereo, and keep levels clean and phase relationships stable. Engineers didn’t need to rebuild studios; a few cables and tweaks unlocked a wider soundstage. Stations could flip between mono and stereo by show or daypart, flexing around interference and audience habits. With a strong local signal and decent receivers, AM stereo could compete head-to-head with FM on presence and clarity, especially for classic rock, soul, and country that benefit from stereo spread and transient punch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;policy-versus-physics&quot;&gt;Policy Versus Physics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the twist most listeners never hear: many limits people blame on AM—thin bass, narrow bandwidth—trace to policy, not physics. Allocations, crowded &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Medium_wave&quot;&gt;dial spacing&lt;/a&gt;, and conservative audio roll-offs aim to reduce interference but also shave tone. When spectrum is less congested, gear is aligned, and processing is smart, AM stereo can breathe. That’s why the YouTube demos stun. They’re snapshots of a path where engineering met taste at the right moment. In places like Canada, Australia, and Japan, you can still find AM stereo signals. A handful of U.S. stations and hobbyists keep the flame alive, sometimes with vintage exciters, sometimes with updated decoders that pull airy detail from modest antennas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-it-wont-return&quot;&gt;Why It Won’t Return&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why doesn’t it return now? Receivers are scarce, car dashboards prioritize streaming, and the brand of AM is cemented as talk-first. Yet the history carries a useful lesson. Distribution wins when standards are clear, hardware is ubiquitous, and the experience is obvious. AM stereo had two out of three but missed the moment for the third. Still, there’s joy in the chase. If you can find a station, or even a well-captured demo, listen with fresh ears. You’ll hear a reminder that radio’s surprises live in the spaces between policy, persistence, and passion—and that great sound sometimes hides in plain sight on a band most of us wrote off too soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 06:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/am-stereo-lost-legacy</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/am-stereo-lost-legacy</guid>
                
                <category>Episodes</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Why Satellite Radio Sounds Mushy</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Satellite radio promises endless choice, but many careful listeners notice something off the moment they switch from &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/FM_broadcasting&quot;&gt;FM radio&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crutchfield.com/ISEO-rgbtcspd/learn/what-is-hd-radio.html&quot;&gt;HD Radio&lt;/a&gt;, or a high‑quality &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whathifi.com/advice/high-resolution-audio-everything-you-need-to-know&quot;&gt;streaming audio&lt;/a&gt; source: the sound turns soft, narrow, and oddly lifeless. That impression isn’t elitism; it’s the predictable result of heavy compression, legacy constraints, and business incentives that reward channel count over fidelity. Typical music channels on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.siriusxm.com/&quot;&gt;Sirius XM&lt;/a&gt; run around 48 kbps and talk channels can drop to 16 kbps, far below the 320 kbps listeners expect from premium streaming or the full resolution of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.qobuz.com/us-en/info/hi-fi-guide/cd-quality-vs-hi-res-myths-and183347&quot;&gt;CD-quality audio&lt;/a&gt;. When you stack those numbers next to services designed for sound first, the differences show up as dulled transients, smeared cymbals, gritty voices, and a stereo image that feels pinned to the dash instead of floating in front of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-technical-core&quot;&gt;The Technical Core&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The technical core lives in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.soundguys.com/audio-codecs-15352/&quot;&gt;audio codecs&lt;/a&gt; and bandwidth. Sirius and XM historically used proprietary systems, leaning on &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Psychoacoustics&quot;&gt;psychoacoustics&lt;/a&gt; to predict what your ear won’t miss. At moderate settings, these algorithms can be convincing; at low bitrates, they become audible, especially in complex music with sustained highs or dense mixes. Every satellite channel must share a finite slice of spectrum, and when a merger doubles the catalog but not the bandwidth, something has to give. The result is a numbers game that favors variety, exclusives, and breadth of programming over the sparkle and space that make audio feel alive. Listeners who compare back to back hear it immediately; those who don’t switch sources often may simply adapt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;streaming-changes-the-game&quot;&gt;Streaming Changes the Game&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Streaming shifts the calculus but doesn’t erase it. The Sirius XM app can deliver up to 256 kbps, which reduces artifacts and restores some depth. Still, many music platforms push &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whathifi.com/advice/spotify-tidal-apple-music-amazon-music-which-streaming-service-sounds-best&quot;&gt;higher bitrates&lt;/a&gt; or even &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.qobuz.com/us-en/info/hi-fi-guide/lossless-vs-lossy-audio-formats183174&quot;&gt;lossless streaming&lt;/a&gt;, and they operate without the satellite-era spectral squeeze. Even more telling is how local control changes outcomes. On FM and HD Radio, and on modern streaming stacks, engineers set the processing chain: &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pre-emphasis&quot;&gt;pre-emphasis&lt;/a&gt;, multiband dynamics, clipping control, and loudness targets. With care, these chains preserve transients, expand stereo width, and keep speech intelligible without sandpapering the top end. Poor choices still ruin the day—over‑limiters, cheap encoders, or misguided loudness wars—but at least creators own the knobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;consumer-awareness&quot;&gt;Consumer Awareness&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do most people notice? Only when flaws grow obvious or when someone demonstrates an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.soundonsound.com/techniques/ab-testing&quot;&gt;A/B comparison&lt;/a&gt;. Human hearing adapts quickly; convenience and uninterrupted playback often beat small fidelity gains. That pragmatism explains why satellite radio can remain “good enough” for a wide audience while &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.headphonesty.com/2021/01/what-is-an-audiophile/&quot;&gt;audiophiles&lt;/a&gt; and radio pros wince. Yet there’s a strategic edge for anyone who does care: better sound becomes a brand signature. Stations and shows that protect dynamics, respect stereo, and avoid brittle processing keep listeners longer, reduce fatigue, and invite word of mouth. Over time, that edge compounds, especially as more cars ship with better &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnet.com/tech/home-entertainment/dacs-everything-you-need-to-know/&quot;&gt;DACs&lt;/a&gt; and cleaner signal paths that expose flaws.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;making-the-upgrade&quot;&gt;Making the Upgrade&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want the upgrade, start simple. Compare your car’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/FM_broadcasting&quot;&gt;FM&lt;/a&gt;, HD Radio, satellite, and phone stream on the same track. Note the presence of air around vocals, the shimmer of cymbals, the weight of bass notes, and the stability of the stereo image. If you run a station or a podcast, audit your chain end to end: source quality, mix headroom, loudness standard, encoder choice, and delivery bitrate. Avoid starving the encoder; a few more kilobits can rescue ambience and transients. For listeners, choose sources that match the moment: satellite for breadth and coverage, HD Radio or high‑bitrate streaming when you want to lean in and actually feel the music breathe. Quality is a choice, and the tools to get there are already in your pocket.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 05:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/why-siriusxm-sounds-mushy</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-siriusxm-sounds-mushy</guid>
                
                <category>Episodes</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Tunwall Radio: A Lasting Legacy in Broadcast Engineering</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Coaxial switch controller manufacturer &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tunwallradio.com/&quot;&gt;Tunwall Radio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; has announced plans to close following the upcoming retirement of its owners, Steve and Leslie Tunwall. The company will accept orders through December 2025, with production scheduled to conclude sometime in the first quarter of 2026. Founded in 2004 with a single switch controller, Tunwall Radio has grown to serve broadcasters for over two decades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the years, &lt;strong&gt;Tunwall Radio&lt;/strong&gt; expanded its product line to include dual, multi-switch, and advanced &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Simple_Network_Management_Protocol&quot;&gt;SNMP-enabled&lt;/a&gt; units. Their widely-used &lt;a href=&quot;https://tunwallradio.com/trc-series-controllers-2&quot;&gt;TRC Series&lt;/a&gt; featured &lt;strong&gt;programmable logic controllers&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Programmable_logic_controller&quot;&gt;PLC&lt;/a&gt;) and universal switch compatibility in a compact design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steve Tunwall is also recognized for designing and building &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phasor_(radio)&quot;&gt;AM directional phasor&lt;/a&gt; and transmitter control systems—solutions found in broadcast sites across the U.S. and Canada.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steve Tunwall engineered one of our &lt;strong&gt;station switchers&lt;/strong&gt; for two different FM stations. Each was equipped with both a main and backup transmitter. His innovative system allowed routing between their respective &lt;strong&gt;main antennas&lt;/strong&gt; or a &lt;strong&gt;shared backup antenna&lt;/strong&gt;, featuring impressive cable routing, sophisticated PLC programming, and robust SNMP functions throughout. The result was truly a &lt;strong&gt;work of heart&lt;/strong&gt;—providing exceptional flexibility, reliability, and control to our facility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tunwall controllers, including models from the TRC Series, currently operate in AM, FM, and TV transmitter sites throughout North America. Their programmable and universal compatibility design, along with SNMP and PLC integration, has made them an essential part of modern &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Broadcasting&quot;&gt;broadcasting&lt;/a&gt; infrastructure and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fcc.gov/engineering-technology&quot;&gt;FCC&lt;/a&gt; compliance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Warranty support for all products will remain in place following the company’s closure. Resources and technical support will continue to be available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://tunwallradio.com&quot;&gt;Tunwall Radio’s official website&lt;/a&gt; after production ends, ensuring that broadcasters who rely on these controllers will not be left without assistance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steve and Leslie Tunwall would like to thank their customers and broadcast equipment dealers for their support and loyalty over the last 21 years. Their dedication and engineering skill have left a lasting legacy in broadcast technology.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 07:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/tunwall-radio-closing-down</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/tunwall-radio-closing-down</guid>
                
                <category>Engineering</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Annual Christmas Music Format Takeover: A Radio Survival Strategy</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s that time of year again and suddenly your favorite radio station has ditched its entire identity to become a 24/7 Mariah Carey jukebox. Welcome to the annual &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christmas_music_radio&quot;&gt;Christmas music radio format&lt;/a&gt; takeover, where perfectly good stations temporarily abandon their programming to become holiday jukeboxes for the next month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some stations genuinely do this for the ratings boost. Others? They’re just keeping the lights on until they can unveil whatever new format the corporate overlords have planned for January.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-strategic-christmas-flip&quot;&gt;The Strategic Christmas Flip&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://barrettmedia.com/2025/09/30/why-all-christmas-radio-formats-still-deliver-huge-ratings-every-holiday/&quot;&gt;all-Christmas radio format&lt;/a&gt; has become a staple of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adult_contemporary_music&quot;&gt;Adult Contemporary radio&lt;/a&gt; in particular. Most stations wait until after Thanksgiving to make the flip, timing it to hit the sweet spot between holiday fatigue and actual Christmas prep mode. The format works because it taps into pure nostalgia, playing songs from the 1940s through today that have somehow remained culturally relevant despite being older than most active radio formats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most stations run about 250 songs in their core playlist, with the format typically ending on December 25 or 26. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nielsen.com/insights/2025/the-record-q4-audio-listening-trends/&quot;&gt;Nielsen data shows&lt;/a&gt; that AC stations see a significant listening boost when they make the switch. People genuinely love this stuff once the calendar flips to late November.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The timing of the flip is critical. Go too early and you risk listener fatigue before Thanksgiving. Go too late and you’ve already lost ground to competitors who flipped weeks ago. It’s a delicate dance, and programmers stress about it every single year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-placeholder-strategy&quot;&gt;The Placeholder Strategy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s where it gets interesting. Not every station flipping to Christmas actually plans to return to its regular format. &lt;a href=&quot;https://radioinsight.com/headlines/289296/2024-post-christmas-format-change-watchlist/&quot;&gt;Some stations use the holiday format as a placeholder&lt;/a&gt;, keeping the frequency warm while corporate figures out what comes next. It’s the radio equivalent of those “under new management” signs that stay up for six months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Christmas format is perfect for this because it requires minimal staffing, the playlist practically programs itself, and advertisers still buy time. You can run a skeleton crew through the holidays, collect ad revenue from jewelry stores and car dealerships desperate to move inventory, and then flip to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Contemporary_hit_radio&quot;&gt;Top 40&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sports_radio&quot;&gt;Sports Talk&lt;/a&gt; or whatever focus group testing says will work in January.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For listeners, it’s bait and switch. For owners, it’s just smart business. For the staff? Well, let’s talk about that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;life-behind-the-christmas-console&quot;&gt;Life Behind the Christmas Console&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As someone who DJed during a Christmas format stint, here’s what nobody tells you about the experience. It is relentlessly, soul-crushingly exhausting. The first week is fun. You get to play the classics, people call in with requests, there’s genuine holiday cheer in the air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By week three, you’ve heard every variation of “Winter Wonderland” ever recorded. You know exactly which version of “Silent Night” is 3:02 and which is 3:04. You can identify the opening notes of any &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/All_I_Want_for_Christmas_Is_You&quot;&gt;Mariah Carey holiday track&lt;/a&gt; within 0.2 seconds, and not in a fun way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jacobsmedia.com/radios-rising-costs-of-burned-out-employees-wearing-all-those-hats/&quot;&gt;Radio burnout&lt;/a&gt; is real in this industry, and the Christmas format accelerates it like nothing else. The repetition is relentless. The songs are engineered to be cheerful, which somehow makes them more maddening when you’re on your fourth shift this week and it’s only December 8th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-listener-experience-gap&quot;&gt;The Listener Experience Gap&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the disconnect. Most listeners genuinely enjoy the format. They hear a few songs on their commute, maybe catch an hour or two at the office, and it adds a pleasant seasonal vibe to their day. They’re not wrong to like it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the on-air talent? We’re living in a Christmas music pressure cooker. Eight-hour shifts of the same 250 songs, day after day, for four to six weeks straight. There’s a reason &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbc.ca/radio/asithappens/as-it-happens-wednesday-edition-1.3371855/dj-locks-himself-in-studio-plays-last-christmas-by-wham-24-times-1.3371859&quot;&gt;some DJs have famously rebelled&lt;/a&gt;, like the Austrian DJ who barricaded himself in the studio and played “Last Christmas” 24 times in a row until his own daughter called in to make him stop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s not holiday spirit. That’s a cry for help wrapped in jingle bells.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-january-reset&quot;&gt;The January Reset&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What happens after December 26 varies wildly. Some stations flip back to their regular format on December 26 at 12:01 AM, like they’re releasing hostages. Others milk it through New Year’s Day. A few stations, usually the ones that were using Christmas as a placeholder, &lt;a href=&quot;https://radioinsight.com/headlines/245484/2022-post-christmas-format-change-watchlist/&quot;&gt;unveil completely new formats&lt;/a&gt; in the first week of January.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the DJs and staff who made it through, there’s a collective sigh of relief. No more arguing about whether to play the Bing Crosby or Frank Sinatra version of a song. No more fielding angry calls from listeners who think you’re playing too much Michael Bublé or not enough traditional carols.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just regular programming. Regular music. Regular amounts of sanity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-bottom-line&quot;&gt;The Bottom Line&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Christmas music format isn’t going anywhere. It’s too profitable, too predictable, and too beloved by enough people to ever disappear. Stations will keep flipping, listeners will keep tuning in, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bridgeratings.com/radios-christmas-music-dilemma&quot;&gt;programmers will keep debating&lt;/a&gt; the perfect flip date like it’s a matter of national security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if you’re enjoying those holiday tunes on your evening drive, just remember to appreciate the DJ who’s been living in a winter wonderland for the past month. They’re smiling through the pain, one “Jingle Bell Rock” at a time. And come January, they’ll finally be free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until next November, anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 05:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/christmas-music-format-takeover</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/christmas-music-format-takeover</guid>
                
                <category>Industry</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>How to Protect Barix Audio Codecs from Radio Broadcast Hijacking</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Over 600 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aareff.com/en/barix-instreamer-and-exstreamer-audio-codec-set/&quot;&gt;Barix Instreamer and Exstreamer&lt;/a&gt; devices are sitting exposed on the public internet right now, discoverable through &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ituonline.com/how-to/how-to-discover-iot-devices-with-shodan/&quot;&gt;Shodan&lt;/a&gt; searches by anyone with basic technical knowledge. If your radio station uses Barix equipment for your &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Az5W_1dnJMc&quot;&gt;studio-to-transmitter link&lt;/a&gt;, your audio airchain could be completely compromised without proper security measures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Labor Day weekend 2025 attacks on stations like KPOG in Des Moines and KRLL in Missouri weren’t isolated incidents. They were wake-up calls for an industry that’s collectively behind on cybersecurity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-labor-day-weekend-attacks&quot;&gt;The Labor Day Weekend Attacks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During Labor Day weekend 2025, hackers hijacked multiple radio stations through vulnerable Barix audio codecs. KPOG, an LPFM station in Iowa, suddenly broadcast explicit content and fake &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emergency_Alert_System&quot;&gt;Emergency Alert System&lt;/a&gt; messages. KRLL in Missouri suffered the same fate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The common thread? Both stations used &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.barix.com/&quot;&gt;Barix equipment&lt;/a&gt; to send audio from their studios to their transmitter sites. The devices were directly accessible from the internet, making them easy targets for exploitation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-barix-devices-are-vulnerable&quot;&gt;Why Barix Devices Are Vulnerable&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.radioworld.com/news-and-business/news-makers/barix-founder-and-cto-bangs-security-drum&quot;&gt;Johannes Rietschel&lt;/a&gt;, founder and CTO of Barix, has been sounding the alarm on this issue for years. The Switzerland-based company has sold approximately 1.4 million audio over IP devices worldwide since 2001. Tens of thousands of second-generation Instreamer encoding devices and Exstreamer decoding devices, released in 2003, are still in use at stations today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem isn’t the devices themselves. Barix has never marketed these as plug-and-play, all-in-one appliances. The Exstreamers are, at their core, generic &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Audio_codec&quot;&gt;IP audio decoders&lt;/a&gt; that require proper network security configuration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-the-attacks-work&quot;&gt;How the Attacks Work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hackers use automated search engines like Shodan to locate exposed devices on the public internet. All they need is an IP address and operating port of a device. Once located, poorly secured Barix codecs become an easy entry point into a station’s audio airchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If an attacker gains access to a station’s Barix equipment, they can inject any audio content they want. This includes explicit material, fake emergency alerts, or even execute a complete &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Denial-of-service_attack&quot;&gt;distributed denial of service attack&lt;/a&gt; that renders the entire network unusable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-core-security-problem&quot;&gt;The Core Security Problem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twenty years ago, there wasn’t much talk about IT security in broadcasting. Radio stations praised Barix equipment for its ease of setup and cost-effectiveness. The reliability of these devices became both a blessing and a curse, as stations installed them and forgot about security entirely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2015, several high-profile breaches of Barix devices led to an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fcc.gov/&quot;&gt;FCC investigation&lt;/a&gt;. Yet the problem persists today. Budget cuts, scant technical staff, and the “if it ain’t broke, don’t fix it” mentality have left hundreds of stations vulnerable to attack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;vpn-tunneling-the-gold-standard&quot;&gt;VPN Tunneling: The Gold Standard&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rietschel’s recommendation is clear and absolute. Barix devices should never be fully exposed to the internet. The gold standard for security is implementing a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_private_network&quot;&gt;VPN tunnel&lt;/a&gt; between your studio and transmitter site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A VPN creates an encrypted connection that makes your Barix equipment invisible to the outside world. Even if your studio and transmitter are on two separate LANs, a properly configured VPN keeps everything secure behind firewalls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;barix-reflector-service&quot;&gt;Barix Reflector Service&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For stations without in-house IT support, Barix offers the Reflector Service, launched with Streamguys over 15 years ago. This service matches authenticated Barix decoders and encoders and forwards the stream between them. Both devices stay protected behind firewalls and remain invisible to the public internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Reflector Service costs a modest monthly fee but was designed specifically for this security situation. It’s a turnkey solution for stations that lack the technical resources to implement VPN tunneling themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stream-pull-configuration&quot;&gt;Stream Pull Configuration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another alternative is Barix’s “stream pull” method, known as BRTP. This configuration allows the Exstreamer decoder to sit on a dynamic IP address behind a firewall and pull a stream from an Instreamer in the studio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The studio still needs a public IP address, but only one specific port needs to be forwarded. A properly configured &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Firewall_(computing)&quot;&gt;firewall&lt;/a&gt; can limit access so the device isn’t detectable on sites like Shodan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;port-forwarding-risks&quot;&gt;Port Forwarding Risks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many stations configure their Barix equipment with simple port forwarding, thinking this provides adequate connectivity. It doesn’t. Port forwarding exposes your devices directly to the internet, making them discoverable and vulnerable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rietschel compared this approach to making your home printer available to the world, then being surprised when hackers drain all the ink. Any &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_of_things&quot;&gt;IoT device&lt;/a&gt; with an open port accessible from the outside internet is vulnerable, regardless of manufacturer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;industry-expert-insights&quot;&gt;Industry Expert Insights&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fletcher Pride from Family First Radio Network, Shane Toven from Frandsen Media, and other industry experts emphasize that securing broadcast equipment is no longer optional. The next generation of broadcast engineers often deals with IT security daily and understands these concepts intuitively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smaller stations should start by talking with whoever originally set up their Barix equipment. If the system was successfully paired in the first place, the station has the technical capacity to secure the devices properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;next-generation-barix-devices&quot;&gt;Next-Generation Barix Devices&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Barix has offered a next generation of audio devices for about seven years, equipped with recent security features. However, even with newer models, Rietschel’s core warning remains absolute. Never put any IoT device on the public internet without proper security measures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reality is that legacy equipment will remain in service for years to come. Upgrading to newer devices is helpful, but not a substitute for proper network security practices like VPN tunneling and firewall configuration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;actionable-steps-for-station-engineers&quot;&gt;Actionable Steps for Station Engineers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, check if your Barix equipment is exposed on Shodan. Search for your station’s IP addresses and see what shows up. If your devices appear in search results, they’re vulnerable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, implement VPN tunneling between your studio and transmitter site if technically feasible. This is the most secure approach and should be your primary goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third, if VPN implementation isn’t immediately possible, consider the Barix Reflector Service or stream pull configuration as interim solutions. These provide significantly better security than direct internet exposure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-bigger-picture&quot;&gt;The Bigger Picture&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Barix hijacking incidents are part of a larger trend in broadcast cybersecurity. As the radio industry pushes more critical systems into the cloud and relies on internet connectivity for essential functions, the attack surface grows exponentially.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Securing your audio codecs is just one piece of the puzzle. Stations need comprehensive cybersecurity strategies that protect every internet-connected device, from &lt;a href=&quot;/tags/stl/&quot;&gt;STL equipment&lt;/a&gt; to automation systems to emergency alert decoders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;technical-fluency-matters&quot;&gt;Technical Fluency Matters&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For years, the radio industry has preached being nimble in areas like podcasting, marketing, and video. Technical knowledge, particularly in cybersecurity, should be at the top of that list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe it’s a younger staffer who’s more fluent in this area. Maybe it’s bringing in an outside IT consultant. Either way, your station deserves the same level of network security you’d expect at home or in any modern office environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Radio stations are community resources and trusted sources of information, especially during emergencies. Allowing your broadcast infrastructure to remain vulnerable doesn’t just risk embarrassing on-air incidents. It potentially compromises public safety.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 05:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/barix-codec-security</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/barix-codec-security</guid>
                
                <category>Episodes</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Why Microsoft&apos;s Windows Update Process Is a Time Sink for Broadcast Engineers</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’re a broadcast engineer pulling double duty as IT support, you already know the drill. You walk into the station planning to work on transmitter maintenance or optimize your STL link. Instead, you spend three hours troubleshooting why a workstation won’t finish installing updates, or worse, why an automation system won’t boot after an overnight update went sideways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft’s Windows Update process has become one of the most frustrating aspects of managing broadcast technology infrastructure. For engineers at smaller stations who wear multiple hats, it’s not just annoying. It’s a massive time sink that pulls you away from the work that actually keeps your station on the air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-update-process-shouldnt-be-this-hard&quot;&gt;The Update Process Shouldn’t Be This Hard&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/troubleshoot-problems-updating-windows-188c2b0f-10a7-d72f-65b8-32d177eb136c&quot;&gt;Windows Update&lt;/a&gt; works, it’s invisible. But when it doesn’t, you’re stuck running command line tools like DISM and SFC, clearing update caches, stopping and restarting services, editing registry keys, and maybe even performing an in-place upgrade just to restore functionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/troubleshoot-problems-updating-windows-188c2b0f-10a7-d72f-65b8-32d177eb136c&quot;&gt;Microsoft’s official troubleshooting guide&lt;/a&gt; lists dozens of potential error codes. Each one represents a path down the rabbit hole. Is it corrupted files? Permission issues? Insufficient disk space? A conflict with third-party software? Maybe the Windows Update service itself is broken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recent updates have made things worse. In October 2025, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/microsoft/microsoft-fixes-0x800f081f-errors-causing-windows-update-failures/&quot;&gt;Microsoft acknowledged&lt;/a&gt; that the KB5050094 update was causing 0x800F081F errors due to missing language packs. The fix required either another patch or an in-place upgrade using Windows installation media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, the August 2025 security updates broke &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tomshardware.com/software/windows/microsofts-august-2025-security-updates-are-breaking-recovery-tools-on-windows-10-and-windows-11-pcs&quot;&gt;Windows reset and recovery tools&lt;/a&gt; on nearly every supported version of Windows 10 and Windows 11. Users attempting to use the “Reset this PC” feature found that the process would start and then immediately roll back. Microsoft released an emergency out-of-band patch, but by then the damage was done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-broadcast-station-ripple-effect&quot;&gt;The Broadcast Station Ripple Effect&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a single engineer managing the IT stack at a radio or TV station, these failures are more than technical headaches. They’re operational emergencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A workstation that won’t complete updates becomes unreliable. It might freeze unexpectedly. It might fail to boot. And if that workstation runs something critical, like traffic software, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.boisestate.edu/hrs-job-levels-job-standards/job-standard-for-broadcast-engineer/&quot;&gt;automation systems&lt;/a&gt;, or playout control, you’ve got dead air risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same goes for studio systems. Modern broadcast operations are built on &lt;a href=&quot;https://fullymodulated.com/posts/uptime-kuma-for-radio-engineers/&quot;&gt;IP-based infrastructure&lt;/a&gt;. STL links run over IP. Automation talks to the network. Even transmitter monitoring is web-based. When Windows decides it’s time to install updates at 3 a.m. and something goes wrong, you find out when you get a call that the station is off the air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://help.broadcastradio.com/support/solutions/articles/101000535053-temporarily-pausing-windows-10-updates&quot;&gt;Broadcast Radio’s support documentation&lt;/a&gt; explicitly warns about the risks. Updates can redetect hardware, reinstall drivers with default settings, or enable features like Audio Enhancements that break soundcard performance. And if an update is already installed and waiting for a reboot, leaving the system in that state for days can cause severe instability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;microsoft-keeps-breaking-things&quot;&gt;Microsoft Keeps Breaking Things&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pattern has become predictable. Microsoft releases a cumulative update. Within days or weeks, widespread reports emerge of failures. The company acknowledges the issue. Then it releases either another patch or a registry workaround.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In August 2025, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/microsoft/microsoft-fixes-streaming-issues-triggered-by-windows-updates/&quot;&gt;Windows updates caused severe stuttering and lag&lt;/a&gt; with NDI streaming software. This impacted broadcasters using &lt;a href=&quot;https://obsproject.com/&quot;&gt;OBS&lt;/a&gt; and other tools for remote production. Microsoft initially suggested a workaround involving NDI transport protocol changes. A fix didn’t arrive until September.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also in August, &lt;a href=&quot;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/release-health/status-windows-server-2025&quot;&gt;smartcard authentication failures&lt;/a&gt; followed the October 2025 update. Systems using CSP-based RSA certificates suddenly couldn’t authenticate. Microsoft deployed a Known Issue Rollback to resolve it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;October brought more chaos. The KB5066835 update &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/daveywinder/2025/10/26/act-now---microsoft-issues-emergency-windows-update-as-attacks-begin/&quot;&gt;broke WinRE recovery tools&lt;/a&gt;, leaving USB keyboards and mice completely nonfunctional in the recovery environment. It also caused localhost connection failures that rendered some systems essentially unusable. Microsoft issued KB5070773 as an emergency fix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These aren’t minor bugs. They’re core functionality failures that Microsoft’s own testing should have caught.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-command-line-gauntlet&quot;&gt;The Command Line Gauntlet&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When updates fail, you end up at the command line. The standard fix workflow looks like this. Open Command Prompt as administrator. Stop the Windows Update service, BITS, Cryptographic Services, and MSI Installer. Rename the SoftwareDistribution and catroot2 folders. Restart the services. Run DISM with &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/Online /Cleanup-Image /RestoreHealth&lt;/code&gt;. Run SFC with &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/scannow&lt;/code&gt;. Reboot. Try the update again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe it works. Maybe it doesn’t. If it doesn’t, you start digging through CBS.log to identify corrupted files, download the specific cumulative update from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.catalog.update.microsoft.com/&quot;&gt;Microsoft Update Catalog&lt;/a&gt;, extract the .msu and .cab files, manually copy missing files into a source folder, and run DISM again with the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/Source&lt;/code&gt; parameter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not an exaggeration. &lt;a href=&quot;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/troubleshoot/windows-server/installing-updates-features-roles/fix-windows-update-errors&quot;&gt;Microsoft’s own documentation&lt;/a&gt; describes this exact process as the fix for Windows Update corruptions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a broadcast engineer who needs to be at a transmitter site, this kind of troubleshooting is a productivity killer. You’re not improving infrastructure. You’re fighting with an update system that should be invisible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;registry-hacks-and-workarounds&quot;&gt;Registry Hacks and Workarounds&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the fix involves editing the registry. To manually unpause Windows updates without triggering automatic downloads, you edit &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\SOFTWARE\Microsoft\WindowsUpdate\UpdatePolicy\Settings&lt;/code&gt; and change &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;PausedFeatureStatus&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;PausedQualityStatus&lt;/code&gt; to 0. Then you delete five time-related entries in &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\SOFTWARE\Microsoft\WindowsUpdate\UX\Settings&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to force a manual update check from the command line? That’s not straightforward either. You can trigger &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;w32tm /resync&lt;/code&gt; for time updates or use PowerShell modules like &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;PSWindowsUpdate&lt;/code&gt;, but there’s no single, reliable built-in command to force an update scan without also triggering automatic installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These workarounds exist because Microsoft’s update system is opaque and doesn’t give users enough control. The system assumes it knows best. When it doesn’t, you’re stuck digging through &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.askwoody.com/forums/topic/how-to-unpause-windows-updates-without-using-the-resume-updates-button/&quot;&gt;community forums&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/Windows10/comments/lp8o6g/command_line_to_triggerforce_a_windows_update/&quot;&gt;Reddit threads&lt;/a&gt; for solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-forced-obsolescence-problem&quot;&gt;The Forced Obsolescence Problem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now layer on Microsoft’s hardware requirements for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/windows-11-specifications&quot;&gt;Windows 11&lt;/a&gt;. The operating system requires &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/enable-tpm-2-0-on-your-pc-1fd5a332-360d-4f46-a1e7-ae6b0c90645c&quot;&gt;TPM 2.0&lt;/a&gt;, Secure Boot, and a CPU from Intel’s 8th generation or AMD’s Ryzen 2000 series or newer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/lifecycle/products/windows-10-home-and-pro&quot;&gt;Windows 10 support ended&lt;/a&gt; on October 14, 2025. Machines that don’t meet Windows 11’s requirements are now officially unsupported. That includes millions of perfectly functional computers with 7th-gen Intel processors, older Ryzen chips, or motherboards without firmware TPM support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For broadcast stations running older but stable hardware, this is a disaster. A Dell workstation from 2016 with a Skylake i7 processor can run Windows 10 flawlessly. It handles automation, playout, and office tasks without issue. But Microsoft says it’s obsolete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Critics, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dGj0rVZGfuk&quot;&gt;former Microsoft engineers&lt;/a&gt;, have called out the arbitrary nature of these requirements. While TPM 2.0 and Secure Boot provide security benefits, the CPU restrictions are less defensible. Older chips can run Windows 11 fine in terms of performance. Microsoft excludes them to reduce driver support complexity and push hardware-based security features, but the practical result is forced obsolescence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The environmental impact is staggering. Microsoft is &lt;a href=&quot;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/answers/questions/3932394/windows-11-arbitrary-restrictions-and-environmenta&quot;&gt;contributing to e-waste&lt;/a&gt; by forcing users to discard functional hardware. Guillaume Pitron and other experts have documented the resource scarcity and environmental toll of mining rare earth metals for electronics. Making millions of working computers “obsolete” accelerates that damage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-stations-can-do&quot;&gt;What Stations Can Do&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re managing Windows systems at a broadcast facility, here’s what actually works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pause updates aggressively.&lt;/strong&gt; Use &lt;a href=&quot;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/deployment/update/waas-configure-wufb&quot;&gt;Group Policy&lt;/a&gt; or registry tweaks to delay feature updates and control when quality updates install. Schedule updates during off-peak hours, and never let them auto-install during critical dayparts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Test updates on non-critical systems first.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t deploy the latest cumulative update to your automation server the day it drops. Wait a week. Let other people find the bugs. Check &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/&quot;&gt;BleepingComputer&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.com/&quot;&gt;The Register&lt;/a&gt; for reports of widespread issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep offline installers and bootable media ready.&lt;/strong&gt; Download cumulative updates from the Microsoft Update Catalog and store them locally. Have a Windows 10 or Windows 11 USB installer on hand for in-place upgrades when the update system completely breaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Document your workarounds.&lt;/strong&gt; When you find a fix, write it down. Build a runbook for common Windows Update failures specific to your environment. You’ll need it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consider alternatives for critical systems.&lt;/strong&gt; If possible, run automation and playout on dedicated hardware with tightly controlled update policies. Some stations keep critical systems on &lt;a href=&quot;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/lifecycle/products/windows-10-home-and-pro&quot;&gt;LTSC editions&lt;/a&gt; of Windows that receive far fewer updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-bigger-picture&quot;&gt;The Bigger Picture&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft’s update process isn’t just inconvenient. It’s a fundamental design failure that wastes time, breaks systems, and forces expensive hardware upgrades on functional machines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a broadcast engineer juggling transmitter maintenance, network optimization, and day-to-day IT support, Windows Update failures can easily consume days of work per year. That’s time you’re not spending improving infrastructure, upgrading facilities, or solving real problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The forced obsolescence through TPM and CPU requirements makes it worse. Stations running perfectly good hardware are now stuck choosing between paying Microsoft for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.engadget.com/computing/microsoft-has-ended-windows-10-support-but-heres-how-to-get-an-extra-year-for-free-125118044.html&quot;&gt;Extended Security Updates&lt;/a&gt;, upgrading to Windows 11 on unsupported hardware using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tomshardware.com/how-to/bypass-windows-11-tpm-requirement&quot;&gt;registry hacks&lt;/a&gt;, or replacing thousands of dollars worth of equipment that still works fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It shouldn’t be this hard. An update system should be reliable, predictable, and transparent. Microsoft’s isn’t. Until that changes, broadcast engineers will keep spending too much time fighting with Windows instead of doing the work that matters.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/windows-update-nightmare</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/windows-update-nightmare</guid>
                
                <category>Engineering</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>KNAC Returns: Legendary Rock Station Relaunches in California&apos;s High Desert</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;At midnight on Halloween, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/KBUE&quot;&gt;KNAC&lt;/a&gt; returns to FM radio in California’s High Desert, 30 years after signing off 105.5 FM with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/RIPMagazine/posts/this-week-in-1995-knac-closed-its-doors-after-bidding-us-all-farewell-with-an-em/1046642680834402/&quot;&gt;Metallica’s “Fade to Black”&lt;/a&gt; on February 15, 1995. The question isn’t whether nostalgia can fuel a comeback, it’s whether a terrestrial FM station can recapture what made KNAC legendary in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-glory-days-were-real&quot;&gt;The Glory Days Were Real&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.playlistresearch.com/la/knac.htm&quot;&gt;KNAC 105.5 FM&lt;/a&gt; launched its “Pure Rock” heavy metal format on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/groups/6686619556/posts/10159509798489557/&quot;&gt;January 8, 1986&lt;/a&gt;, and instantly became something special. The launch came after four consecutive sold-out &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Iron_Maiden&quot;&gt;Iron Maiden&lt;/a&gt; shows at the Long Beach Arena proved that heavy metal was more than an underground fad. Despite a weak signal that barely covered the LA market, KNAC built a fiercely loyal fanbase that turned the station into a cultural phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From 1986 to 1995, KNAC was the soundtrack for Southern California metalheads. The station played &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/AC/DC&quot;&gt;AC/DC&lt;/a&gt;, Iron Maiden, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Judas_Priest&quot;&gt;Judas Priest&lt;/a&gt; when other stations wouldn’t touch them. It helped break bands like &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metallica&quot;&gt;Metallica&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Megadeth&quot;&gt;Megadeth&lt;/a&gt; into the mainstream. KNAC sold merchandise nationwide, influenced the heavy metal scene, and eventually earned induction into the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.playlistresearch.com/la/knac.htm&quot;&gt;Rock and Roll Hall of Fame&lt;/a&gt; in 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The station’s bumper stickers and T-shirts became &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.latimes.com/archives/la-xpm-1994-11-03-ca-58260-story.html&quot;&gt;ubiquitous symbols of rock rebelliousness&lt;/a&gt; throughout Southern California. Even people in Oklahoma knew what KNAC was because major artists wore the station’s shirts. That’s how deep the cultural impact ran.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-streaming-years-kept-the-brand-alive&quot;&gt;The Streaming Years Kept the Brand Alive&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the FM signal went dark in 1995, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.metalsucks.net/2025/10/29/historic-rock-station-knac-to-return-to-radio/&quot;&gt;KNAC.com&lt;/a&gt; kept the brand alive as an internet radio stream starting in February 1998. I didn’t grow up in Southern California, so I never experienced the original 105.5 FM broadcast. But in high school, I spent hours streaming KNAC.com, discovering bands and diving deep into the world of heavy metal from hundreds of miles away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The internet stream proved that KNAC’s appeal transcended geography. Without the constraints of terrestrial radio, KNAC.com could be even more adventurous with its playlist. It maintained the attitude and the community that made the original station special, just without the FM dial position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-challenge-of-returning-to-fm&quot;&gt;The Challenge of Returning to FM&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now KNAC is back on FM, broadcasting on &lt;a href=&quot;https://radioinsight.com/headlines/316004/knac-to-relaunch-in-californias-high-desert-on-halloween/&quot;&gt;96.9 in Lenwood/Barstow, 94.9 in Baker, and 99.7 HD3 in Mountain Pass&lt;/a&gt;, covering the I-15 corridor from Southern California to Las Vegas. &lt;a href=&quot;https://radioinsight.com/headlines/316004/knac-to-relaunch-in-californias-high-desert-on-halloween/&quot;&gt;Heftel Broadcasting&lt;/a&gt; is relaunching the brand with Gonzo Greg Spillane, who worked his way from intern to morning host at the original station, now serving as President of Rock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The setup sounds promising. The opening hours will feature archival clips, legendary voices like Thrasher and Jack Trash, and those infamous moments that made KNAC’s reputation. The playlist will mix modern acts like &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Five_Finger_Death_Punch&quot;&gt;Five Finger Death Punch&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bad_Omens&quot;&gt;Bad Omens&lt;/a&gt; with classics from &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/M%C3%B6tley_Cr%C3%BCe&quot;&gt;Mötley Crüe&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bon_Jovi&quot;&gt;Bon Jovi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But can it work in 2025?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-made-knac-special-cant-be-replicated&quot;&gt;What Made KNAC Special Can’t Be Replicated&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original KNAC succeeded because of timing, circumstance, and a willingness to take risks that most &lt;a href=&quot;/categories/radio/&quot;&gt;broadcasters&lt;/a&gt; wouldn’t. The station operated with a weak signal in a market dominated by giants like KMET and KLOS, which gave it underdog credibility. It played music that wasn’t on other stations because it had nothing to lose. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.latimes.com/archives/la-xpm-1994-11-03-ca-58260-story.html&quot;&gt;heavy metal scene was exploding&lt;/a&gt; in the mid-1980s, with bands selling out arenas and going platinum despite limited radio support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those conditions don’t exist anymore. By 1994, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.latimes.com/archives/la-xpm-1994-11-03-ca-58260-story.html&quot;&gt;the LA hard-rock community had become virtually nonexistent&lt;/a&gt;, and the culture around hard-rock music had undergone massive social and musical upheaval. Today, radio itself has been diminished by streaming services, podcasts, and algorithm-driven playlists. The rebellious attitude that defined KNAC has to navigate 2025 broadcast regulations and corporate ownership structures that didn’t exist in the same way 40 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-high-desert-location-might-be-perfect&quot;&gt;The High Desert Location Might Be Perfect&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the twist: KNAC’s new location in California’s High Desert might be exactly what it needs. The station isn’t trying to compete in the Los Angeles market where expectations and competition would be overwhelming. It’s serving a corridor of highway towns and desert communities that actually need a real rock station with personality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spillane told &lt;a href=&quot;https://blabbermouth.net/news/knac-returns-to-airwaves-with-new-era-of-pure-rock&quot;&gt;Blabbermouth&lt;/a&gt;, “The spirit of KNAC was never about living in the past, it was about kicking down the door to the future.” That’s the right mindset. If the new KNAC tries to be a museum piece replaying 1980s glory, it’ll fail. If it uses the KNAC spirit to break new bands and serve its actual community, it has a chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nostalgia-alone-wont-be-enough&quot;&gt;Nostalgia Alone Won’t Be Enough&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want KNAC to succeed. I want it to recapture some of that attitude that made the original station legendary. But nostalgia alone won’t sustain a &lt;a href=&quot;/tags/fm-radio/&quot;&gt;terrestrial radio station&lt;/a&gt; in 2025. The new KNAC needs to be genuinely good radio, not just a tribute act trading on a famous name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pieces are in place. Spillane understands what made KNAC special because he lived it. The station will stream globally on knac.com and knac.fm, combining terrestrial reach with internet distribution. The playlist respects the legends while featuring modern bands. Former personalities are returning alongside new voices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But will it have the same rebellious edge that defined Pure Rock in 1986? Will it break new bands and influence the rock scene like the original did? Will it matter to listeners in 2025 the way it mattered to metalheads in 1990?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time will tell. I’ll be listening when KNAC returns at midnight on Halloween, hoping that some of that old magic survived the 30-year gap. The spirit might still be there. Whether it can thrive in 2025’s radio landscape is the real question.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 17:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/knac-relaunch-halloween</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/knac-relaunch-halloween</guid>
                
                <category>Industry</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>